art
wonder wonder
we wonder what we are
looking into the infinite
and finding something relevant
to find a frame
around which something catches our
attention
and share the essence with another
to use a brush
a chisel a bow a pin
to allow my mind
to allow one mind to connect to caress
another mind
to convey across the space between
that which is inside to make it outside
again
[Music]
yes this this is the this is the
vibration between
two souls where the concept of
one is conceived given birth
and then through physical means is
expressed
and received by others
and it is a distillation of experience
for example the painter distills what
they see they use their consciousness
to choose which parts
they are going to portray which parts
they're going to leave
out they manage the materials the
movements of their body
their perceptions to to
try and bring a
sense of what is in front of them
art as artifice is artificial
as a way of
freezing a frame a perspective
that draws attention to the element
to a curve to a pause
to a line to a spark
that ignites and gives birth to another
whole
perspective the magic of freezing that
frame in a way that makes it move
it makes it animate from one mind to
another
how how do we make
this thing over and over again
i agree i wonder does it
does it live outside of us
is it only human
[Music]
if we think about
a painting of a tree
there is absolutely nothing
of the tree in the painting it is merely
some smudges of pigment and oil
mashed up together upon a canvas of
fabric with bits of stone in it
there's nothing of the tree there
and the painting of the tree will not
look like the photograph of the tree
either it will have some special
essence and is this the essence of art
when we listen to a piece of music
which is just vibrations
from our eardrums buzzes clicks
why are we suddenly transformed into a
pastoral or a dance
how is it that
what we might consider real
is not considered art and yet the
essence
can be extracted and portrayed
in a way that gives a different
deeper more alive version
of the real the real has
accents that i increase
appreciation from one to another
to allow the flow and expansion
beyond the limitations of what one alone
may be able to perceive a wonder of it
weaving in and out until
what is perceived is a glimpse
of the infinite
in enjoying art together as a community
rather than just the one mind to the
other mind we then
engage in a in a community
ever fascinates a community vibration
a lifting up of the spirit and the soul
in a sense
of oneness with our fellow man
regardless of
religion to go and listen to a beautiful
mass in a wonderful wonderful cathedral
is a deeply moving and elevating
and enriching experience for those who
go
and this wonderful sense of collective
beauty essence core
a rising up of who we are to something
better a call to something
more fine
fractal shades
utterances tastes
elements that bring forth
the sense of identity and
the fragility of identity as a
separate self as it
melds and falls away the window
through which one can see another
across time across dimensions across the
infinite
the act of knowing participatory
real depth that moves beyond
knowing who one thinks
one is
the boundaries to solve and
all this
art then as a as a bridging
between souls and individuals
perceptions understandings
connections distillations
the observed is made
into a sharing the consciousnesses
as they perceive the world find a
communication and a vibration
art is our bond
art is our mutual communication
art is the place where we find
ourselves as god and reflect each other
and reflect
to reflect to find
to reveal to add
and to subtract leaving
more than was originally
perceived how is it possible
a magician to perceive one
and the same inside and out
the frame which appears to limit creates
an infinite window
how is it possible to remember
to the beginning of time to the end of
time
and a sparkle upon a page
upon a mind upon a nude
gives one pause to listen
there is a depthiness to art
a depthiness that reaches back to the
beginning of mankind's first
thoughts and their marks upon cave walls
to the grandest pieces of
design and architecture painting
films it is
a vast space of creative
endeavors and communications it is most
glorious the most glorious reflection
of our humanity and our love
our relationships our striving
and and our desire to share
and connect with our fellow human beings
it is where the group mind
where the co-creative space
between all humanity lies
is that the end that's the end